## KENNETH BLACK

**FULL STACK DEVELOPER | PORTLAND, OR** 

Portfolio <a href="http://lawlietblack.com">http://lawlietblack.com</a>

GitHub <a href="https://github.com/LawlietBlack">https://github.com/LawlietBlack</a>

LinkedIn <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kennethrblack">https://www.linkedin.com/in/kennethrblack</a>

Email Kenneth.Black@live.com

#### **Career Summary**

Applied Physics graduate, tenacious problem solver, self-taught developer. Far from the average code school grad, by the time I finish Epicodus I will have 2 years of software development experience totaling over 4,000 hours, spanning 5+ languages and nearly a dozen frameworks. Coding combines my love of problem solving with the satisfaction I get from building things and has become a passion of mine, something I truly enjoy.

#### **Work Experience**

**Web Developer** – SimB & Co. – 2017 Improved an existing Rails REST API, made custom web scrapers, added and refactored tests with rspec.

**Discovery Expert** - Stahancyk, Kent & Hook - 2014-2015 Compiled, indexed and maintained discovery documentation and spearheaded the transition to paperless discovery.

**Lab Assistant** – U. of Oregon Physics Dep. - 2010-2011 Maintained and analyzed data from the rooftop solar array and machined parts for a specialized electron microscope.

**Student Intern**— Social Security Administration - 2010 Reviewed cases using console database programs and managed dynamic priorities in a busy office environment.

#### **Education**

Bachelor of Science - University of Oregon Graduated in Applied Physics, 2011 Ruby on Rails Track – Epicodus Full Stack Web Development, 2016-2017

**Full Stack Web Development** – FreeCodeCamp.com Obtained Front End Development, Data Visualization, and Back End Development Certifications, 2015-2016

Code Oregon – TeamTreehouse.com

Completed Front End Web Development, Full Stack
JavaScript, Python, and Flask Tracks, 2015-2016

## **Key skills**

#### Interpersonal

- Leadership experience
- Enjoys collaboration
- Quick, voracious learner
- Tenacious problem solver
- Mentoring and tutoring experience
- Works well on a team or independently

#### **JavaScript**

- AngularJS 1.X/2
- React / JSX
- D3.is
- Gulp

- JavaScript ES6/Babel
- Node/express/npm
- AJAX
- Jasmine/Mocha

#### Ruby

- Sinatra
- rspec/Capybara/TDD
- Rails
- ActiveRecord ORM

## Python

Django

Flask

#### Java

Spring

Jersey

### **Development**

- CRUD/ RESTful APIs
- oAuth1&2/Passport
- Test Driven Development
- Git/GitHub
- Windows/Mac/Linux OS
- MongoDB
- Yeoman/Scaffolding
- Heroku/Deployment
- Terminal/SSH/Nano
- Bower

### **Design Implementation**

- HTML5 / CSS3
- Responsive Design
- Sass/Bourbon
- Bootstrap/Materialize

# **Projects**

#### Quinta Esencia Taller <a href="http://bit.ly/217Zkel">http://bit.ly/217Zkel</a>

Public site for Quinta Esencia Taller, an environmental education nonprofit organization based in Columbia.

#### Definitely Real Quotes <a href="https://bit.ly/drqlb">https://bit.ly/drqlb</a>

Fake quote sharing site inspired by John Oliver's segment on misappropriated quotes built with AngularJS, Node, Express, MongoDB, oAuth, and Sass

#### Dungeon Game <a href="http://bit.ly/rldlb">http://bit.ly/rldlb</a>

A roguelike dungeon game built with React and Sass. Players can explore the dungeon, find gear, fight monsters, gain experience, and level up.

#### Meteor Strike Map <a href="https://bit.ly/mmslb">https://bit.ly/mmslb</a>

D3.js map showing meteor impact sites where the relative size of the point corresponds to the mass of the meteor and the color of the point represents the meteor class.

#### Conway's Game of Life <a href="http://bit.ly/gollb">http://bit.ly/gollb</a>

Conway's game of life built with React and Sass with grid size, generation speed, pause/play, and randomize functionality.